- The best thing about the iPhone Air
is actually how much it
seems to have freed Apple up
to make the Pro phones even more pro.
(slow dramatic techno music)
(slow dramatic techno music continues)
(slow dramatic techno music fading)
Have you noticed that?
These new Pro phones are
thicker than last year,
more room inside for bigger batteries,
and a vapor chamber, and a bigger camera.
It's not quite on the
level of the Ultra phones,
but this is the most maximalist
that an iPhone has ever
felt, and I like it.
But also, let me let you in
on a little not-so-secret secret.
The Pro phone is always
the best selling one.
Like this year, the iPhone
Air is the most interesting
and it's getting the most YouTube
clicks and the most views,
but then the Base 17 is
more than ever the one
that most people should
get and the best deal.
But it turns out the
Pro Max, specifically,
by far, is the most
popular, by sales numbers.
I was gonna try to find a
way to show you guys this,
you know, channel sponsor Dbrand,
they make a accessory for
every single model of iPhone,
and so their sales distributions
kind of match Apple's.
And this is the distribution this year.
Over half our Pro Maxes,
and between the two Pros,
that's like 90% of orders.
So yeah, it's fun to watch
Apple kind of walk this line
between being a more pro
phone than ever before
and this maximalist new design
and everything they're doing,
but also, being literally
the most mainstream phone
of all-time.
Like the cameras.
Might as well start there, right?
The cameras are the most pro thing
about the Pro iPhone every year.
And on one hand, no professional
would say, "Oh yeah,
thank gosh I have eight
lenses now in my smartphone,"
like Apple seems to want us to believe.
It clearly has three.
But, the three cameras you get
are more evenly matched than ever.
The primary and ultra-wide
are essentially unchanged
from last year, but the
telephoto gets a big update.
It's now also a 48-megapixel camera
and it's a 4X telephoto lens.
Last year was a 5X but only 12-megapixels.
So, this new one feels
like a more natural,
portrait focal length.
It's roughly a hundred
millimeter equivalent
and all of your zoom shots
will have much more detail
and much less noise, thanks to
the sensor being much larger
and much higher resolution.
Now, I will give them credit
for the specific 2X zoom increments,
because while they are
not actually new lenses,
they do specifically process
each of the images shot
in a 2X crop to be slightly
sharper and better looking
than just a pure digital crop
on the middle of the sensor.
So, you know, it's not the
level of a pure optical zoom,
but it's better than nothing.
So, I don't know why they only do it
at these focal lengths, honestly.
Either way, it's a really
nice total package now.
Three matching 48-megapixel cameras,
all of which are super reliable,
just as good for casual
shooters as they are
for people who depend on
their iPhone for work,
or maybe who happen to have
an entire YouTube channel
about cars that they happen
to shoot all on smartphones.
(clears throat) Yeah.
Electric G Wagon review
coming to "Auto Focus",
shot on iPhone 17 Pro very soon.
I do still kind of find myself wishing
they made some other improvements,
like the point light problem at night
when you shoot in the dark
and those little flares always show up.
They haven't fixed that at all.
Or even adding 8K video support.
There's a two terabyte iPhone model now.
I feel like 8K video is just
a flip of a switch away,
but not this year.
But you know, the changes
are stacked up nicely
over the years from older Pro phones
like the 13 Pro and the 14 Pro.
It's not a huge difference
versus last year, but it's nice.
Also, what you're watching
right now is ProRes raw footage
from the iPhone 17 Pro,
which I was particularly excited about
because that means I can go
into the new Final Cut Pro 11.2,
I think it is, and I
can literally change ISO
and white balance after I
shoot, which is very useful.
Also, the file sizes are huge.
And there's even another
Pro feature that they added
that they couldn't brand for themselves
because pros already use it and named it,
and that's genlock support,
which basically lets
devices talk to each other
so that they can stay in sync over large,
multi-device shoots.
Pretty sick.
And also the selfie cameras
are more pro than ever
more about that in the 17 Base review.
But yeah, a lot going on with cameras.
So let's be real, 95% of people
who get these phones are
just gonna point and shoot
and these are more capable and
reliable than ever for that.
If you want more in-depth
stuff on shooting
like professionally with this camera,
you can check out Tyler Stalman's review,
which I'll link below.
It's really in-depth and
he shot the whole thing
also on the iPhone.
My favorite thing about
this new Pro iPhone though
is actually the new design.
It's not often that the newest
iPhones actually change a lot
and get thicker and heavier,
but like I said, I
think that's kind of one
of the best things about them coming out
with a separate phone that's
designed just to be super thin,
so that if you want a thin
phone, go get the Air.
But if you don't care about that,
if that's not one of your priorities,
then here's the new Pro,
which goes the other
direction and isn't afraid
of a few extra fractions of an inch.
And I love that it's an all
uni-body metal jacket now.
This is not a glass sandwich anymore.
Literally, the whole body
of the phone is metal now
with glass cutouts at the
back for wireless charging,
and then at the top for those
millimeter wave antenna.
This makes it more durable,
it makes more room inside
for a bigger battery,
which we'll get to in a second,
and there's enough room
for a vapor chamber
for the first time ever in an iPhone.
And then the new plateau at the top,
I actually think it's great.
This is where I've been
putting my index finger
on Android phones for years.
It's like a natural resting
spot to hold up the phone.
Same thing with this one now.
And Corning's Ceramic Shield too,
in case you haven't already
heard, is also clearly awesome
for preventing scratches
to the front glass.
A couple of nitpicks though,
no black color Pro phone?
You sickos.
This is like one of those weird things
that it feels like Apple's
doing just spite me,
where they're making a bunch of products
that should have a
black version but don't.
Like the new MacBook Airs come in silver,
and starlight, and sky
blue, and dark blue.
But no black?
And then the AirPods
Max refresh also comes
in a bunch of colors, and
dark blue, but no black.
We need a dark neutral,
especially because the color
that you pick actually shows up
around the front bezel of the phone.
So you see the color
you pick all the time.
It makes the orange and silver
that much more annoying to me.
(sighs) I told you it was a nitpick.
But then you've probably
also already seen the chatter
about Scratchgate, which
is just how easily it seems
like the anodization layer on top
of the aluminum seems to scratch off
and then reveal the raw
silver aluminum underneath it.
And I kind of don't really
know what to make of this yet.
I feel like this has come up before
with a lot of darker
anodized aluminum phones.
And as a person who rocks
the phone with no case,
I haven't had any issues
with the one I'm using.
I've been tossing it around.
But the JerryRigEverything
test has revealed
that the weakest part that
you could get scratched
or dinged is gonna be around
the tightest corner radii,
like around the camera plateau.
So we'll see how many phones
this ends up affecting.
But we gotta talk about
the insides of this phone
because the redesign is one thing,
but there's even more
going on under the surface.
The A19 Pro chip,
shocker, is pretty great.
It's benchmarked around 20%
faster than the last generation
and when paired with iOS
26 and 12 gigs of RAM now,
these phones feel really quick
and snappy, which is great.
But the extra thickness has also made room
for a vapor chamber for the first time,
and it's actually made a real
difference to the thermals
and the behavior of this phone.
Big shout out to HGX Studio, YouTuber,
who is able to put thermal
cameras on these phones
under load and really visualize this,
but especially compared to the Air,
these phones rarely got any more
than slightly warm to the touch for me.
And as a result, they were able
to actually hold higher frame
rates longer while gaming
and keep the display brightness higher
when recording videos for a long time.
Check out the rest of his
video too, by the way.
It's freaking incredibly well done.
But, it also reminded me about
why, in the Android world,
like gaming phones kind
of have the same effect.
The stuff that makes a
gaming phone really good,
like better speakers
and better performance,
and better screen and big batteries,
well, all that stuff is
awesome for regular use too.
And it's the same deal for the Pro iPhone.
The stuff that makes a
really good Pro iPhone,
like the improved display,
and the much better cameras,
and the thicker, better
build with improved cooling
for shooting videos longer,
and better sustained performance, yeah,
it turns out the masses
buying iPhone 17 Pro Max
also really enjoy nicer screens,
cameras, and batteries too.
Not a surprise.
And we've all been saying for years, "Hey,
just make a thicker phone
and put more battery in it."
I just really feel like
this is another place
where having an iPhone Air
focusing on getting super thin,
let them feel free to go
the total other direction
with the other phones
because if they're gonna
claim the iPhone Air
is all-day battery life, then great,
every single other phone in
the lineup gets even thicker
with bigger batteries.
So the 17 Pro has a 20%
bigger battery than last year,
and the Pro Max actually cracks
the 5,000 milliamp hour mark
for the first time ever,
which is great in iPhone land,
and also 40 watt charging now.
So that's half battery in 20 minutes.
To Apple, that's a big deal.
We welcome a 20%
year-over-year improvement.
Now in Android land, obviously it's,
it kind of looks like nothing,
like it's nowhere near the Ultra phones
with 6,000 milliamp hour
silicon carbon batteries
and 100-watt charging and all that.
But, for a phone that ships in the volume
that the iPhone does, very
happy to see that sort
of improvement when last year's phone
already had really good battery.
The iPhone is also very efficient.
So I am getting a nice five plus hours
of screen on time every day
on not even the bigger phone,
and it's lasting all day
with 30+ percent left.
So, I'm loving it.
And then, there's just all sorts
of other little things too,
like with this screen,
I think this is the first
generation of iPhone
that's had a toggle for PWM dimming.
Now it's buried in the
accessibility settings,
but you can search and find it,
and that is very welcome to many people.
And there's also a slightly noticeable
but better-than-nothing
anti-reflective coating.
But more importantly,
the display gets slightly brighter now
and I noticed that.
It's up to 3000 nits peak.
And satellite connectivity has
expanded to cover messaging
and location sharing too
now, which is useful.
So at the end of the day, the paradox is
that making the Pro iPhones more pro
is actually better for the masses.
And this is the best one yet,
it's the most freed one yet.
And I think, you know,
when they eventually,
if they make some iPhone
Ultra at some point,
I'll probably still want
all of that over this.
But for now, this is good stuff.
Now if you are thinking
about getting an iPhone 17
but you are concerned
about those scratches,
then channel sponsor Dbrand
does have some options for you.
Like this Grip Case, which
I have here in that black.
And it also does a pretty good
job of hiding that plateau,
which if you've seen
Zach's durability test,
it is the most vulnerable spot
for the anodization to chip off.
Alternatively, if you're
more of a clear case person,
you can grab one of their
Ghost Cases instead,
which comes with a lifetime
zero yellowing guarantee
and also a full camera protection.
Fun fact, these are also available
at Best Buy in the US now too.
Both cases check all the boxes
you want in an iPhone case,
like strong MagSafe and
camera control buttons.
But most importantly, they're
both super protective.
And then whichever way you go,
if you wanna round out your protection
with a screen protector,
you can also pick up one
of Dbrand's Prism Protectors.
They're super easy to install.
And if you bundle it
with either a Grip Case
or a Ghost Case, you can use
code M-K-B-H-D at checkout
to save 42% on the Prism.
Pretty sweet deal.
I'll leave a link down below
for you to check 'em all out.
Thanks for watching.
Catch you guys very soon,
still in Techtember,
in the next one.
Peace.
(light upbeat techno music)